Guide to the Daniel Goode Papers MSS.269
Fales Library and Special Collections
Daniel Goode Papers
1950-2016
1974-2004
Fales Library and Special Collections
Goode, Daniel
MSS.269
11.25 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 1 tall manuscript box, 3 small flat boxes, 5 oversize flat boxes, and 2 oversize folders in shared housing
Daniel Goode (b. New York, January 24, 1936) is an American composer and clarinetist, whose work as a composer and performer has done much to introduce non-Western styles and tunings to Western audiences and to Western-style ensembles. The Daniel Goode Papers comprises printed scores, spiral-bound stave manuscript books, performance announcements (posters and cards), music programs, periodicals, staple-bound publications by Goode, catalogs, miscellaneous paper materials, videocassettes, cassette tapes, LP records, a reel of magnetic tape, and CDs.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Daniel Goode in 2010; additonal materials were donated in 2017 and 2019. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2010.269, 2017.171, and 2019.054.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into six series, five of which are arranged chronologically. Series VI. has not been arranged by an archivist. All series, subseries, and folder labels were provided by the archivist.
Series I. Daniel Goode Scores
Series II. Printed Matter
Series III. Video Recordings
Series IV. Sound Recordings
Series V. Data Disks
Series VI. 2019 Accretion
Biographical Note
Daniel Goode (b. New York, January 24, 1936) is an American composer and clarinetist, whose work as a composer and performer has done much to introduce non-Western styles and tunings to Western audiences and to Western-style ensembles.
Goode graduated from Oberlin College in 1957, and received his MA in 1962 from Columbia University, where he studied with Henry Cowell and Otto Luening. Goode also attended the University of San Diego, studying under Kenneth Gaburo and Pauline Oliveros. Goode taught at Livingston College, Rutgers, from 1971 to 1998. While at Rutgers, he founded the Livingston College Electronic Music Studio, serving as its director. Goode's work is influenced by his interest in Indonesian Gamelan and other non-Western modes and techniques, and his work often incorporates extended techniques on clarinet, circular breathing, birdsong, and Nova Scotian and Eastern European folk music. His works are published by Frog Peak Music and Theodore Presser.
Since the early 1970s, Goode has founded, composed for, and performed in various ensembles: Sounds out of Silent Spaces (with Philip Cornder, William Hellerman, Tom Johnson, and others) (1972-1979), Gamelan Son of Lion (with Corner, Barbara Benary, and others) (since 1976), DownTown Ensemble (with Hellerman and others) (since 1983),The Flexible Orchestra (since 2004).
Sources
"Daniel Goode - About." (2011). Retrieved from http://www.danielsgoode.com/about.html.
Benary, B. & Sandow, G. (2001). "Daniel Goode." T he New Grove Dictionary of Music and Musicians, volume 10. 2nd Edition. Edited by Stanley Sadie. London: Macmillan Publishers, Ltd.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact fales.library@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Daniel Goode Papers consist of materials created and collected by Goode in the course of his musical career between 1950 and 2015, including printed scores, spiral-bound stave manuscript books, performance announcements (posters and cards), music programs, periodicals, staple-bound publications by Goode, catalogs, miscellaneous paper materials, videocassettes, cassette tapes, LP records, a reel of magnetic tape, CDs and CD-Rs.
Separated Materials
The following books were removed and cataloged as part of the Fales Food Studies Book Collection. They can be located by searching "Daniel Goode" in BobCat, the NYU catalog.
Good, Daniel (Ed.). (1995). Frog Peak Rock Music Book. Lebanon, NH: Frog Peak Music.
Gaburo, Kenneth (Ed.). (1980). ALLOS: 'Other' Langauge. La Jolla, CA: Lingua Press.
Avant-garde (Music); Composers -- United States -- 20th century; Music -- New York (State) -- New York.; Audiocassettes.; Gamelan.; Minimal music.; Phonograph records.; Magnetic tapes.; Compact discs.; Videocassettes.; Scores.; Music -- Manuscripts.; Musicians -- 20th century; Goode, Daniel; DownTown Ensemble; Gamelan Son of Lion; Corner, Philip
- Series I: Daniel Goode Scores, 210319
  Arrangement
  Subseries are arranged chronologically. Undated material is arranged alphabetically by folder label and placed after dated material.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I comprises stave manuscript books of Goode's compositions, as well as printed scores and performance directions.
  - Subseries A: Scores, 1974-2004, undated; 210323
    - "Circular Thoughts for Solo Clarinet", 1974; 210345 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "The Thrush from Upper Dunakin", 1974; 210346 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Phrases of the Hermit Thrush", 1974-1975; 210347 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Two Thrushes - For 2 Woodwinds", 1975; 210348 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Paths for Piano," "Piano Concerto", 1976; 210349 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Mozart Was a Performance Artist", 1977; 210350 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Hear the Sound of Random Numbers", 1978; 210351 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Circular Thoughts for Gamelan", 1979; 210352 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "The Red and White Cows", 1979; 210353 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Days of Music", 1980; 210354 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Wind Symphony", 1980; 210355 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Switch 'N Pivot Processional", 1981; 210356 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Barry's Catches", 1985; 210357 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Random Chords", 1988; 210358 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Nod-Drama", 1993; 210359 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Contents of "One Page Pieces; Copies; Notes on", 210360 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cover of "One Page Pieces; Copies; Notes On", 1999; 210361 (Box 1, Folder 17a)
    - "One Page Pieces" [from Frog Peak Rock Music Book], undated; 210842 (Box 1, Folder 17b)
    - "OoMPAH for Piano", 2002; 210362 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Pipes, Plates, and High Bars", 2003; 210363 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Interpreting: Text for a Musical Work Composed for the DownTown Ensemble" by Daniel Goode, 2004; 210364 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Octave for Jackson", 2005; 210365 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Toy Symphony" [unrevised], 2007; 210366 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "An Ideal Amen", 2014 (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
    - "Antiphony IV", undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Cage's 'Dream' Dreamed", undated; 210367 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "Caller's Music", undated; 210368 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "Certain Distilling Processes", undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "The Chaco Wilderness", undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Dans Music", undated; 210369 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - "Eine Kleine Gamelan Music", undated; 210370 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Inner Motions" (Part IV), undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Line Studies", 1957 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "The Red and White Cows", undated; 210371 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Semaphores", undated; 210372 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Shaking Music", undated; 210373 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "Slendro Clarinet," "Clarinet in Pelog", undated; 210374 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - "Sonata for Clarinet and Piano", undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Symphony No. 1", undated (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - "Orbits #1", undated; 210375 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "Two Dans Music", undated; 210376 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Two Noter" [uncorrected], undated; 210377 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Untitled", undated; 210378 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Untitled Scores, undated (13)
  - Subseries B: Manuscript Books, 1960-1963; 210324
    - Manuscript Book #1 Sept. '58 - June '60 Manuscript Book #2 June - Sept. 1960, 210379 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Manuscript Book #3 Sept. 1960 - Dec. 1960 Manuscript Book #4 Dec. 1960 Manuscript Book #5 Jan. 1961, 1960-1961; 210380 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Manuscript Book #6 Feb 1961 Manuscript Book #7 March 28, 1961 Manuscript Book #9 August 8, 1961, 210381 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Manuscript Book #10 Dec 22 1961 Manuscript Book #11 Jan 20 1962 Manuscript Book #12 June 21 1962, 1961-1962; 210382 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Manuscript Book #13 Jan. 1963 Manuscript Book #14 Winter '63 (Feb) (Mar) Manuscript Book #15 July 15 1963, 210383 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series II: Printed Matter, 210322
  Series II comprises cards and posters announcing performances, programs from musical performances, periodicals, music company catalogs, and other paper material.
  - Subseries A: Mailers and Announcements, 1976-2001, undated; 210326
    - Daniel Goode Mailers and Announcements 1 of 2, 1976-1997; 210384 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Daniel Goode Mailers and Announcements 2 of 2, 2000-2009, undated; 210385 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      General
      Contains some Flexible Orchestra mailers and announcements.
    - Gamelan Son of Lion Mailers and Announcements, 1989-1991, undated; 210386 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - DownTown Ensemble Mailers and Announcements, 1994, 1995, 2001, undated; 210387 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Subseries B: Programs, 1978-2009, undated; 210325
    - Daniel Goode Programs 1 of 7, 1978-1987; 210388 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Daniel Goode Programs 2 of 7, 1987-1989; 210389 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Daniel Goode Programs 3 of 7, 1990-1994; 210390 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Daniel Goode Programs 4 of 7, 1994-1997; 210391 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Daniel Goode Programs 5 of 7, 2000-2004; 210392 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Daniel Goode Programs 6 of 7, 2004-2010; 210393 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Contains some Flexible Orchestra programs.
    - Daniel Goode Programs 7 of 7, undated; 210394 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Gamelan Son of Lion Programs, 1984-2007; 210395 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - DownTown Ensemble Programs, 1985-2008, undated; 210396 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - SoHo Gamelan Walk, 2009; 210397 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous Papers, 1993, 1999, undated; 210343
    - "Balkan Music Has No Borders", 1993; 210398 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - A Book for Grandmothers (Ruth Goode), 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Computational Linguistics Notes and Readings, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Downtown Ensemble, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Electronic Music Notes and Outlines, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Peter Garland, 2015 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Letter from Vienna" by Dan Goode, 1999; 210399 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Livingston College Faculty Handbook, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Long Distance Elect Checklist, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "A Long Time Ago, Ann and Daniel Thought...", undated; 210400 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Man and His Body, 1960-1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Manuscripts, 1963-1968 (Box 16, Folder 10-12)
    - Notebook, ca. 1971; 277188 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Oberlin College Yearbook, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Onan's Diary Proposal, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Rejection Letters, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
    - Reviews of Julie My Nights and Days, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Rutgers, 1988-1990 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Scores by Other Composers, 1980s-2000s (Box 16, Folder 19-25)
    - Theatrical Studies, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Sound Expression Assignments and Student Exercises, 1970-1979 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Walking, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Subseries D: Periodicals, Catalogs, 1976-2004, undated; 210331
    - Periodicals 1 of 6, 1976-1977; 210401 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Periodicals 2 of 6, 1977, 1985; 210402 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Periodicals 3 of 6, 1986; 210403 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Periodicals 4 of 6, 1988; 210404 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Periodicals 5 of 6, 1991, 1992; 210405 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Periodicals 6 of 6, 1997, 1999; 210406 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Catalogs and Brochures, 1979, 1997, 2000, 2004, undated; 210407 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Publications -- The Epic of Medicine, 1962 (Box 15)
    - Publications -- Catalogs, 1975-1987 (Box 15)
- Series III: Video recordings, 210315
  Series III comprises videocassettes.
  - Subseries A: Video recordings, 210491
    - The Shouting Opera, April 4, 1986; ID: 269.0001; 214078 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0001)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original format: VHS
    - Comp with Sound Finale, 1986; ID: 269.0002; 214079 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0002)
    - Downtown Ensemble and Washington Square Church, June 4, 1988; ID: 269.0003; 214080 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0003)
      Original format: Betamax
    - Gamelan Son of Lion - Digital Master, March 8, 1989; ID: 269.0004; 214081 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0004)
    - Karya: create, 1990; ID: 269.0005; 214082 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0005, Case 269.0005)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Access DVD available.
      Duration: 38 minutes.
    - Son of Lion, May 1, 1991; ID: 269.0006; 214083 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0006, Case 269.0006)
      Duration: 87 minutes.
    - 3% Vision, 1991; ID: 269.0007; 214084 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0007)
      Standard: PAL
    - Alan's for Daniel, undated; ID: 269.0008; 214085 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0008)
    - V.O.I.D. Pauline de Groot, May 12, 1996; ID: 269.0009; 214086 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0009)
    - Alexandra and Jonathan Wedding Day, June 22, 1996; ID: 269.0010; 214087 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0010)
    - Re: Sound, 1/25/1999; ID: 269.0011; 214088 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0011)
    - The Down Town ensemble and Special Guests Conducted by David Gilbert, October 4, 2001; ID: 269.0012; 214089 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0012)
    - 8 Thrushes in Georgia, 2002; ID: 269.0013; 214090 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0013)
    - H.A.C. Chorus ("Again + Again"- DG), 6/12/2004; ID: 269.0014; 214091 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0014)
    - [1] Dan's King @ Loft [2] Concepts for Wire Sculpture, [1] 2005 [2] Febuary 2006; ID: 269.0015; 214092 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0015)
    - Gamelan Son of Lion, undated; ID: 269.0016; 214093 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0016, Case 269.0016)
      Duration: 45 minutes.
    - Untitled, undated; ID: 269.0017; 214094 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0017)
    - Orbits 1972 at Notre Dame University, ID: 269.0028; 214097 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0028)
    - Gamelan Son of Lion, Jogja Festival 1996, ID: 269.0044; 214515 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0044)
    - Re: Sound, February 8, 1999; ID: 269.0049; 214516 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0049)
    - Indoor/ Outdoor/ Fluxns/ Action/ Music Art in General, December 2, 2001; ID: 269.0055; 214530 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0055)
    - Soho Gamelan Walk, December 2, 2001; ID: 269.0056; 214531 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0056, Case 269.0056)
      Original format: MiniDV
      Duration: 51 minutes.
    - Dan at Dartmouth, November 20, 2002; ID: 269.0057; 214532 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0057, Case 269.0057)
      Duration: 56 minutes.
    - The Stone, Daniel Goode, May 15, 2008; ID: 269.0058; 214540 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0058, Case 269.0058)
      Duration: 53 minutes.
    - Alan Glovsky, undated; ID: 269.0059; 214533 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0059)
    - Jody Oberfelder Dance Projects, undated; ID: 269.0064; 214534 (Box 7, Media ID: 269.0064, Case 269.0064)
      Duration: 50 minutes.
  - Subseries B: Separated Materials, 210499
    - Document Removed from "Pauline de Groot at Danspace" VHS, 1996; 210503 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Sound recordings, 210493
  Series IV comprises audiocassettes, reels of magnetic tape, compact disks and CD-Rs, and phonograph records.
  - Subseries A: Sound recordings, 210495
    - Bad Alchemy N2 XXII, undated; ID: 269.0018; 214629 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0018)
      Format: 1/4" audiocassette
      Tape Length: Unknown
    - Excerpts and Condensations from Three Pieces, 1977 - 1978; ID: 269.0019; 214098 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0019)
      Format: 1/4" audio reel
      Speed: 7.5 ips
    - Music from the Tempest, [1964]; ID: 269.0020; 214099 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0020)
    - Tempest Part II., 1964; ID: 269.0021; 214100 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0021)
      Speed:
    - Tempest Tape 26-- I. duet…, [1964]; ID: 269.0022; 214101 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0022)
      Speed: Unknown
    - Tape 27-- Tempest Chorus, [1964]; ID: 269.0023; 214102 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0023)
    - Tape 28-- Tempest I. Trio, [1964]; ID: 269.0024; 214103 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0024)
    - Music Plus One 1968-- Tape 17, ID: 269.0025; 214104 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0025)
    - Short Wave and Geese, September 1969; ID: 269.0026; 214105 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0026)
      Speed: 3.75 ips
    - [1]--Cameron Chisolm at Strathslorne Dance [2]-- Bell- Beat Bowed Barn Gong, [1] August 18, 1972 [2] undated; ID: 269.0027; 214096 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0027)
    - Barn Gongs, 1972; ID: 269.0029; 214106 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0029)
    - [1]-- Hermit Trushes Dunakin [2]-- "Phrases" Bird, circa 1973 - 1975; ID: 269.0030; 214107 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0030)
      Speed: 3 3/4 ips
    - Thrush Chords (Phrases), July 14,1974; ID: 269.0031; 214108 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0031)
    - Phrases of the Hermit Thrush for calr. Solo, string orchestra, 2 flutes: (two performances), August 11, 1980 and April 10, 1981; ID: 269.0032; 214109 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0032)
    - Phrases of the Hermit Thrush for Clarient, String Orchestra and 2 Flutes, April 10, 1981; ID: 269.0033; 214110 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0033)
    - Hermit Thrush - Dub, June 18, 1981; ID: 260.0034; 214517 (Box 8, Media ID: 260.0034)
      Speed: 15 ips
    - C.B. Concerto: Rutgers Concert Band, December 10, 1985; ID: 269.0035; 214518 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0035)
      Tape Length: 90 minutes
    - Bed/ House, April 1, 1987; ID: 269.0036; 214519 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0036)
      Tape Length: [46 minutes]
    - Spain 1990: Sardana/ Cowbellls/ Bird/ Fiesta de el Remedia, June 24, 1990; ID: 269.0037; 214520 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0037)
      Tape Length: [100 minutes]
    - Spain 1990 Tape 2 Santiage de Compostela/ Cathedral Bell, July 7, 1990; ID: 269.0038; 214521 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0038)
    - Yugoslavia, 1991; ID: 269.0039; 214634 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0039)
    - Gamelan in the New World, 1979; ID: 269.0040; 214522 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0040)
      TRT: Unknown
    - Gamezlan in the New World, 1991; ID: 269.0041; 214523 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0041)
    - Grenada Sampler: 1993/ VLF Short wave, ID: 269.0042; 214524 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0042)
    - Grenada 1993 Mel. Proj. VLF, Bird, Short Wave Pros, ID: 269.0043; 214525 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0043)
    - Pornography Made Me Do It...Again!, 1997; ID: 269.0045; 214526 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0045)
      TRT: 4:09
    - Balkan Music/ Side 2-- a traditional Klezner Clarinet tune, November 1998; ID: 269.0046; 214527 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0046)
    - Aviva, undated; ID: 269.0047; 214528 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0047)
    - Mocking Bird/ Wood Thrush from Helyan Forest, December 1998; ID: 269.0048; 214529 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0048)
    - Water Pipes: 458 W. 20th Street - Februarary 26, 1974, February 1999; ID: 269.0050; 214535 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0050)
    - Glendale, Tape III, Sun Night, undated; ID: 269.0051; 214536 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0051)
    - Phrases of the Hermit Thrush, August 1995; ID: 269.0052; 214537 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0052)
    - Two Thrushes/ Phrases of the Hermit Thrush, March 1999; ID: 269.0053; 214538 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0053)
    - Hear the Sound of Random No.s- DG at Beat 1999 Fest, ID: 269.0054; 214539 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0054)
    - Environment Tape I, undated; ID: 269.0060; 214541 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0060)
    - Part 4 Take 1, undated; ID: 269.0061; 214542 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0061)
    - Tulloch Gorum/ Rankins, undated; ID: 269.0062; 214543 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0062)
    - Worm, undated; ID: 269.0063; 214544 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0063)
    - Managua-Matagalpa Music, undated; ID: 269.0065; 214545 (Box 8, Media ID: 269.0065)
    - The Thrush From Upper Dunakyn: St. Joseph's Church, NYC, December 7, 1979; 214636 (Box 8)
      Format: 12" vinyl sound disc
      Speed: 33 1/3 rpm
    - Sleepers - Lull music by Daniel Goode, Doris Hays, Tom Johnson, Alison Knowles, Annea Lockwood, Ilhan Mimaroglu, Ann Silsbee, Pauline Oliveras, 1985; 214637 (Box 8)
    - Solo Performance 1/2 Track, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Bass Clan and Electronics, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - Birds (Part of Selected Chambers), 1977 (Box 9)
    - Water Neshanic in 3 Movements, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Faust Excerpts, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Faust Excerpts, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Orbits, 1971 (Box 9)
    - Bulgarian Folk, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Walpurgus Rhythym, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Fontana Loops, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Faust's Death (Madras Hymn), 1970s (Box 9)
    - Traveling Music (Rehearsal Tape), 1970s (Box 9)
    - Macedonian and Bulgarian Dances, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Morning Music (with Bill Hellerman and Philip Corner), 1978 (Box 9)
    - Ancient Sleeping, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Pomp and Circumstances, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Tape Loops, 1973 (Box 9)
    - Birds Backwards/Forwards/Several Speeds, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Gaburo Antiphony II, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Pacific Sirens Performing, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Pacific Sirens Made from Filtered Ocean Waves Plus Instruments (Robert Erickson), 1969 (Box 9)
    - Scrambled Birds, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Robert Erickson, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Hypnotica Domestica (Performance Tape), 1970 (Box 9)
    - Faust Patch, 1970s (Box 9)
    - River Falls Concert, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Wood Thrush, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Amplified Stream Neshanic, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Phrases, Scrambled Birds, SOB Laugh, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Traveling Music (Rehearsal), 1974 (Box 9)
    - Angus Chisholm, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Hutz, African, Afro-Cuban Jam Session, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Short Discourse on Rhythm, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Water with Backwards Gamelan, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Democracy Rains, 1970s (Box 9)
    - Hermit Thrush, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Wood Thrush and Bell Rows, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Space Music II (Stokes), 1970s (Box 10)
    - Bell Rows and Phrases of the Hermit Thrush (Circular Thoughts), 1970s (Box 10)
    - Solo Performance (Master), 1970s (Box 10)
    - Phrases of Hermit Thrush with Listening Centres, Gongs, and Feedback, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Master - Saul II, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Bell Rows -- The Kitchen, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Amplified Stream -- M. Lytle's Mix, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Democracy Rains -- Daniel Goode with Class, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Concert of Daniel Goode and Phil Corner (Carnegie Recital Hall), 1976 (Box 10)
    - Paths, Chopin, Erotica, 12 Tone; Bells Rows Part Gamelan I and II, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Lukas Foss Echo, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Echoi?, 1968 (Box 10)
    - Gallery Concert III, 1970s (Box 10)
    - Brant and Goode Round for Two Ensembles, 1970s (Box 10)